Rage with the machines.
The Electric State is a science fiction, adventure,
action film directed by Joe Russo.
An orphaned teen hits the road with a mysterious robot to find her long-lost
brother, teaming up with a smuggler and his wisecracking sidekick.
Michelle, played by Millie Bobby Brown.
Keats, played by Chris Pratt.
Dr. Amherst / P.C (voice), played by Ke Huy Quan.
Ted / Wingman, played by Jason Alexander.
Christopher, played by Woody Norman.
Colonel Bradbury / The Marshall, played by Giancarlo Esposito.
The Electric State is a 2025 American science fiction action-adventure
film produced and directed by Anthony and Joe Russo.
Its screenplay by Christopher Markus and Stephen McFeely is loosely
based on the 2018 illustrated novel by Simon Stålenhag.
The film stars Millie Bobby Brown, Chris Pratt, Ke Huy Quan (in a dual role), Jason Alexander, Woody
Harrelson, Anthony Mackie, Brian Cox, Jenny Slate, Giancarlo Esposito and Stanley Tucci.
Plans for a film adaptation were announced in 2017, with Andy Muschietti.
The Russo brothers signed on to direct in December 2020.
Universal Pictures acquired the distribution rights before
Netflix took over the rights in June 2022.
Much of the cast was revealed between June 2022 and November 2024, with
filming taking place in Atlanta, Georgia in fall 2022.
With a reported budget of $320 million, it is one of
the most expensive films ever made.
The Electric State premiered at Grauman's Egyptian Theatre in Los Angeles on
February 24, 2025, and was released on Netflix on March 14.
It received negative reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of man vs machine, artificial intelligence
(a.i.), based on novel or book, technology, dystopia.
The tone is thought_provoking.